((あいつ　まだ赤ん坊だった あんたを捨てたのよ))
We're not desperate enough to beg
a total stranger to train us! Say something, Gon. We have Wing-san.
)
Right, right.
((子供を捨ててでも 続けたいと思う仕事なんだね))
We already have a master, and we don't need anyone else to teach us.
((ハンターって それだけ　すごい仕事なんだね))
You mean that little boy with
messy hair and glasses? The one who never tucks in his shirt?
((あんた　やっぱり あいつの息子だわ))
Do you know him? Do I know him? Wing's one of my students.
((ジンさんに 認めてもらうための最終試験が
Seriously? That's awesome!
彼を捜し当てることなのさ))
So he's become a master now... Time really flies, huh?
)
Does that mean you're pro Hunters?
((彼は俺の知る限り 最高のハンターだ))
Oh, just me. You've passed the secret exam? Yep.
((結局　何が欲しいのか 教えてもらえなくて…)) )
Well, I'm essentially your master's master, so you shouldn't have any
problems with my teaching you.
登木希望？　ダメだよ。
Don't probe for him. He'll notice.
この先　１８歳未満は。
How did you sense him? He let a tiny bit of bloodlust escape.
何か特別な資格か免許がないと…。
The enemy saw a bunch of kids,
and he relaxed for a second.
ん？
Doesn't that mean he's weak?
あっ！　プロハンター!? その年で!?
He immediately concealed his presence again.
いや　こりゃ　失礼 どうぞ　どうぞ。
It was only the slightest bloodlust,
and he quickly concealed it, so he's pretty good.
あ 一応　この書類にサインしてくれ。 大統領でも 書いてもらうことになってる
We couldn't even sense his presence,
let alone locate him.
いわゆる　登るに当たって
What should we do?
死んでも構わないって 例のあれさ。
He's fast on the uptake! This boy's bright.
アドバイスしとくぜ。
If we stick together,
he'll be less eager to attack. I agree.
先客が残した　くさびや足場を 当てにするなよ。
Well, you're right. But that's not what we're going to do.
登れる奴は　大概　丸腰だ。 今　頂上にいる奴も　そうだった。
If I go off on my own, the enemy is one hundred percent
guaranteed to attack me. I'll go south. You boys, go north.
分かった　ありがとう！
Walk five hundred meters without
concealing your presences.
まっ　ヤバいと思ったら すぐ　それを押しな。
Aim for that pillar.
うちのレスキュー班は優秀だ。
Once you get there, use Zetsu,
then rush back immediately! Okay, stalk the stalker—
あっ　落ち…！
Huh?
おい！
Fine, then! Be that way!
はい！
Damned hag...
ヒャ！ アハハハ…！
So long, stupid!
先は長いな。
Huh? I was on full alert, so I'd be ready to react at a moment's notice.
すごい木だ
Yeah.
指を触れた瞬間 そこが生命力に満ちていて
I just cut your hair...
樹木全体と つながっているのが分かる
With my Scissor Hands!
行ける！ 木のささやきに 逆らわず進めば
When I eat the hair I cut, I can learn things about the owner's body
助け…　て… ん？
I will learn everything about your body
助けて…　くれ…。
before I begin to toy with it...
もう少し
Very well.
わっ！
You're lucky.
デッカ！
During that battle, what did you see first?
びくった。
The guy being flipped through the air. Same here.
やぁ！
Her opponent wasn't weak by any means. She's just that strong!
よぉ。 ん？
If he were an in-game character, he'd have a D rank in terms of difficulty. It would have been an instant
game over for you boys.
待ちくたびれたぞ。
That makes the second time I've seen you barely escape death.
ジン。
How long will your good fortune last?
５００ｍ地点から ここまで　何分かかった？
Just call me Bisky. If you insist on an honorific, call me Bisky-chama!
えっと…　２０分くらいかな。
I'll just call you Hag.
まっ 初めてで　それなら及第点か。
Why are you here, Bisky?
食え。 うん。
Well, I'm here to clear the game, but I'm mainly after a jewel. A jewel?
あ！
It goes in restricted slot #81...
いい眺めだろ。
Blue Planet. What about you boys?
曇りの日は　一面　雲海になる。 うん。
We're here to clear the game, obviously. Actually, my dad made this game.
ねぇ　ジン。 ん？
Oh?
聞いていい？ おう 答えねえかもしんねぇけど。
I'm looking for my dad, so I thought this game might contain a lead.
ジンが欲しいものって何？
Who's your dad? Ging Freecss. Ging?!
うん…。
You know him? You bet I do! He's famous.
今　目の前にないもの　だな。
Chairman Netero once said
目の前にないもの？
he was one of the top five Nen users...
俺がハンターになろうと思ったのは…。
Bisky, if you'd be willing to
postpone your treasure hunt, please teach us Nen! You've finally come around?
うるせ!!
I'm a lot tougher than Wing.
俺がハンターになろうと 思ったのは
What about you? I'll be fine.
当時　俺が行きたかった場所に 入るのに
Take out all your cards.
ハンターが 一番　現実的だったからだ。
Book. I'm going to give you a chance.
その場所は ある王族の 埋葬施設とされてたんだが
You must evade their attacks for two weeks! If you're successful, I'll let you escape.
一切　口外しないことを条件に 信頼に足る団体
If you're knocked unconscious or can't stand...
しかも　自費での調査しか 許されない状態だった。
I will kill you. I just have to avoid their attacks, right?
実質　そりゃ 調査できないって話だ。
It doesn't matter what I do to them? Sure.
見返りも業績も求めず
But there's one rule.
大金をつぎ込める奴なんて まず　いない。
You aren't allowed to leave this crater. If you break this rule, you lose, and I'll kill you.
俺は逆にチャンスだと思った。
What about us?
プロハンターって信頼を得れば
The same rules apply.
金は何とかなるからな。
If you leave, or fail to defeat
him after two weeks, you'll be punished.
１５歳の時に 特定非営利活動法人を設立して
You're the Bounty Hunter Binolt, right? Yeah.
王墓の調査と修繕を行った。
There's a bounty on his head, as well.
その前の　ライセンスを 取得してからの２年は
He's a brutal murderer.
ずっとネットで　考古学マニアの サイトやブログ巡りさ。
Begin!
法人設立のため １０人くらい必要だったからな。
Why are you standing around?
俺は　いつも　今　俺が 必要としてるものを追ってる。
He's trying to heal up! Are you going to let him?
どうでもいいくらいにな。
If he weren't injured, I would have lost my eye!
よっと。
We can't get close to him...
ネットで知り合って　オフ会で 意気投合した　そいつらは みんな　俺より年上で
Should I use this? But while I charge up, he won't stay still.
普通の会社員や 院生やフリーターだったりした。
Gon, let's make this a battle of attrition. Attrition? You get some rest.
連中は　法人設立にかかわる雑事を 進んでこなし
I'll keep an eye on him, and use these to attack. We'll switch every six hours. Rocks? That's a good idea.
なけなしの生活費から 寄付までくれた。
That's exactly what I need...
念願かなって 王墓の中に足を踏み入れた時 俺が　一番　嬉しかったのは
If I can rest like this for a week,
I'll be more or less recovered. Once I'm healed, I can finish them off.
そいつらは 今も無償で役員をしながら
Makes sense. Damn!
今は？ あっ？
Binolt may be injured, but making him uncomfortable
in half a day is still impressive. They're conscious that their lives
are on the line in this fight.
今は　何を追ってるの？
Not bad at all.
今か…　少し説明がいるな。
These boys are raw gems!
ゴン 俺達が登った　この木は何だ？
That rock-hard conviction in his eyes. That hidden, bottomless potential.
えっ？　世界樹でしょ？ そうだな。
If properly cut through training,
he can be completely transformed...
下では　この木を何て紹介してた？
Like a diamond!
世界で　一番　高い木で １７８４ｍあるって。 うん　それは間違ってない…　な。
And this boy is a cool, calm blue. He may look fragile, but with the right amount of heat, he can
achieve semi-permanent strength... Like a sapphire!
だが　この木の真実は
Why does my heart skip
成長の止まった若木だ。
whenever I see something
waiting to be polished?
えっ。 栄養が足りなくて
I'll train them well!
これしか育たなかった 世界樹なんだ。
What? A forest of rocks.
大気圏を越えて　なお　デカくなる。
Game over, pops!
この世界の外側で。
Stop, Killua!
この世界って…。
Why did you stop me, Gon?
お前も　よく知ってる世界地図さ。
We still have plenty of time.
えっ？
Let's continue until we're both
able to take him alone. Huh?
外側から来た外来種。
I'll slice you up! Sure, but let's wait until tomorrow.
学校じゃ教えてくれない真実だ。
You should get some rest.
常識のある大人は
You've been slowing down.
あえて　パンドラの箱に 触れまいとしている。 ん？
True. If it takes both of us to beat a single
injured, exhausted man, we won't stand a chance
against any of the rest.
とてつもなく大きな世界の ほんの一部だってことにな。
You won't be able to fool their
acute antennae now.
ある時代のある地域の 選ばれた人間は
Binolt, your potential pales
in comparison to theirs.
分かったか？ えっ？
Oh, my wallet's missing.
俺が欲しいものは 今も昔も変わらない。
Really? You had it a moment ago.
目の前にない　何かだ。
Excuse me... You dropped this...
「資格」　「契約」。
He's slowing down. No, we're getting faster.
俺は　まだ この中の一つも手に入れてない。 だが　別に　急いでいない。
Practice pays off that much more
道中を楽しんでる最中だ。 だから　もし
when you're fighting an equal for your life.
道草を楽しめ。
Damn...
きっと　そっちに転がってる。
I never... I never wanted
あっ！
I wasn't expecting any gratitude...
これ　カイトに頼まれてたんだ。
That's enough.
ジンに返しておいてくれって。
There's no way I can defeat you.
おう　そうか。
Kill me. Why? We won't kill you.
そん時の傷が
to lead a normal life.
棺の中から出て来たのは
Gon... You're flawless, a perfect gem.
それが その扉からじゃないと
But that pure nature could be your undoing. Well, let's head for Masadora.
ハハハハ…！
Damn... Masadora's about seventy kilometers away. That's a three-hour trip, at most. Seriously?
道草を楽しめ。
G.I. Tutorial Today, we're introducing the card Blue Planet.
大いにな。 欲しいものより大切なものが きっと　そっちに転がってる。
Blue Planet
A gemstone with an
incomparable blue shine.
Its composition matches
no known minerals,
so it's named for its
otherworldly nature. It's one of the reasons Bisky is playing the game. She's going through all this just for a stone? That hag has weird taste...